<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Symbios.wiki]]></title>
  <link href="http://symbios.wiki/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://symbios.wiki/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-01T16:28:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://symbios.wiki/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Symbios]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portfolio for MIT Media Lab 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/portfolio/MIT-Media-Lab/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/portfolio/MIT-Media-Lab</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One and Three Obelisks, 2016</p>

<p>One and Three Obelisks is a contemporary take on Kosuth’s One and Three Chairs. My interest in his piece is loosely inspired by Graham Harman’s interpretation of Delanda’s Assemblage Theory. Kosuth’s simple chairs forced the locus of his piece to be the chair that wasn’t present, the Real chair which is never captured in representation or reification. My extension of his logic uses a specific Egyptian obelisk. Instead of focusing on object, image, and definition, I instead chose to focus on commodity, simulation, and historical document. This specification of an object as a commodity, an image as a simulation, and a definition as a historical document is an attempt to extend the locus of the piece to not just include a Real obejct, but also the temporality of that object. Perhaps this juxtaposition of commodity, simulation, and historical document conjures a Real sculpture.</p>

<p>Borromean Resistance: Performance (X+1), 2016</p>

<p>Borromean Resistance is a collaboration between sarah olympia, Dorothy Lam, and myself. Performance (X+1) continued the work of Piece 1, proposing new models of activism as feedback in complex systems. It was a four-part interactive computing system that probes the intersection of technology, art, and activism. Drawing on the tension between the urgent need for political change called for in movements such as climate activism and the lure of abstraction in art, the installation engages the viewer in challenging questions about representation, efficacy and collective action. Three interactive stations allow the viewer to experience and critique different conceptual models of social and political action. As the fourth element, an open discussion explores the tensions between art and activism, abstraction versus action, futility versus utility, and digital versus analogue interaction. The show was largely inspired by the systems art movement and the work of Hans Haacke.</p>

<p>birds_without_space, 2016</p>

<p>(video still)</p>

<pre><code>Inspired by Brancusi’s infamous “Bird In Space”, @birds_without_space represents the 9 most “evolutionarily distinct and globally endangered” avian species in the world due to human-related habitat loss. (You can check out edgeofexistence.org for their complete list of species). The accompanying video piece seeks to explore the banality of such ecological horrors by flattening the traditional sculpture into a 3D render synthesizing some the largest contributors of habitat loss for these birds.
</code></pre>

<p>The images and video in the piece are all cropped at 4x5 ratio and rotated 90 degrees which maximizes the amount of space media can take up on Instagram. In choosing Instagram as the platform and framing the piece in this way I hope to provide these birds with the maximum amount of virtual space where they can repopulate symbolically through the sharing of their image. By appropriating the medium of hyper-real renderings most often used in architecture/realty and advertising, I hope to subvert these practices which allow profiting from the exploitation of land.
When discussing ecological horrors such as the loss of species I find the language of the Sublime and the Real to help express the ineffable magnitude of such losses. In “The Return of the Real” Hal Foster discusses techniques such as illusionism, gaze, and repetition which artists such as Gober, Sherman, and Warhol, respectively, have used in order to focus their art upon the Real.
The scene takes place in an old-fashioned office which could be anyone’s. This recreation of a hyper-real office space was motivated Foster’s comment that “illusionism [for Gober] is employed not to cover up the real with simulacral surfaces but to uncover it in uncanny things”. Living in contemporary American society makes participating in our economy of environmental havoc inevitable; we are constantly surrounded by the disastrously mundane things such as timber, meat, and electricity. The POV camera was chosen to show this trapped subject, browsing Instagram, as self-surveying, “not in phenomenological immanence (I see myself seeing myself) but in psychological estrangement (I am not what I imagined myself to be)”.
The extremely nontraumatic and docile act of scrolling through Instagram is repeated in a choppy loop, ad infinitum, like a reversal of Warhol’s famous “Death and Disaster” series. Here our collective trauma is not a visible horror, but a mass complacency due to the filtering of horror through the hyper-real lens of media. We have seen too many “gruesome picture[s] over and over again”, and now they “don’t really have any effect”. Thus, this complacent scrolling “must be repeated” but only serves to remind us of the disasters we are ignoring. This is where Foster claims “the Real ruptures the screen of repetition” and it is the now the subject that is “touched by an image”.</p>

<p>Music Stuff, 2013-2016</p>

<p>Isomov - Interference (LP)
<a href="https://soundcloud.com/isomov/sets/isomov-interference">https://soundcloud.com/isomov/sets/isomov-interference</a>
This album was complete in in 2013 and was largely inspired by the book Godel Escher Bach and the short story The Last Question by Isaac Asimov. The album spans many genres of contemporary electronic music and is composed using ideas of story and song structure related to the works of Iannis Xenakis. Each song was composed to fit specifically into a theme of increasing scale and self-reflective iterative structure.</p>

<p>Completed in 2013</p>

<p>Isomov - Phonogram (Unreleased Excerpts)
<a href="https://soundcloud.com/isomov/isomov-interlude/s-pUUSk">https://soundcloud.com/isomov/isomov-interlude/s-pUUSk</a>
In the track Interlude I first tracked down few existing samples of a castrato, namely Alessandro Moreschi, ever recorded. I was intrigued that there was such little evidence for such a culturally symbolic practice in music. Through a bit of research i learned that there is a contemporary male soprano singer, Radu Marian, who suffers from a hormone deficiency, which is similar to hormonal changes in castrati. By chance, there are recording of Marian and Moreschi singing the same song, Ave Maria. I spent some time to time warp these tracks as to have the pair sing a duet together. Through the use of modern technologies, a unique collaboration through time, space and cultures was made possible. This track makes up the background of a club track which utilizes samples from phonograph records, like those used to record Moreschi, and a melody which was composed using a mixture of purely synthesized sounds and a recorded instrument to mirror the duet in the background.</p>

<p>Various Tracks
<a href="https://soundcloud.com/internet_ghetto/sugarquote-everyone-is-here-but-its-just-you-and-me-free-dl">https://soundcloud.com/internet_ghetto/sugarquote-everyone-is-here-but-its-just-you-and-me-free-dl</a>
<a href="https://soundcloud.com/xenonymsss/isomov-pseudometa">https://soundcloud.com/xenonymsss/isomov-pseudometa</a>
<a href="https://soundcloud.com/tsaik/tehraj-sugarquote-remix">https://soundcloud.com/tsaik/tehraj-sugarquote-remix</a>
<a href="https://soundcloud.com/isomov/you-feel-perfect-5-12-16-2/s-WmKTP">https://soundcloud.com/isomov/you-feel-perfect-5-12-16-2/s-WmKTP</a>
With these tracks I mostly hope to convey my technical expertise in music production and song-writing which I hope to utilize at the media lab.</p>

<p>Flamin’ Hot Rainforests, 2016</p>

<p>(video still)</p>

<p>In 2015, 6.4m acres of Indonesian rainforest were burned down from reckless slash and burning to make space for palm oil crops. These rainforests are the second most biodiverse areas on Earth and the CO2 emissions from the fires are more than the annual emissions from major economies such as the UK and Japan. Source.
To represent such a sublime atrocity is futile, and so I believe the medium should reflect this futility. I was quite inspired by Talwst Santiago’s approach to this problem in his Minimized Histories dioramas, which show tiny caricatures of hate crimes against blacks throughout history. Because most Americans’ experiences of foreign lands, such as Indonesia, and of cataclysms, such as fires, have been filtered through the lenses of tourism and movie VFX, respectively, I decided to use languages to reflect the deficiencies of representing this sublime ecological disaster.</p>

<p>Tsaik - Tehraj (Music Video), 2015</p>

<p>(video still)</p>

<p>Tsaik’s production is an interesting mix of self-sampling, sound synthesis, and intense recomposition - a sort of simulated jazz. To complement their rich production techniques and natural feel, I wanted to create a layered world featuring nature, generative organisms, and self-reflective video effects - a sort of simulated Ernst Haeckel. I settled on the use of stock footage of nature (some photographed by tsaik), plant-like L-systems, datamoshing , and 3D models of kaleidoscopes.
I’m personally interested in the speculative realist perspective on virtual realities: how juxtaposing the virtual and the actual can allow us to face the Real and encounter the sublime. With that in mind, I appreciate generative art for its ability to create lifelike artistic organisms through simulation and its relation to the computational sublime.
    L-systems are models of self-similar plant growth and they allow you to create very complex structures with a few simple rules. The complexities of a biological plant are hard to replicate so simply, but the growth of l-systems has an uncanny resemblance with that of plants that exist in nature. This makes them a good mirror for the scenes presented in the video. L-systems are often used in video games to quickly generate natural landscapes.
    Datamoshing is an old technique used by the glitch community, but I really enjoy the natural impressionist feel they can give to digital video, like the tape-saturated feel of Tehraj. It’s also a great visual technique to complement the glitchy editing and fills used by tsaik.
    The kaleidoscopes were inspired by an old blog post and are particularly interesting to me because of how strange it is to have a virtual solid be rendered using reflective surfaces within an already-virtual model of plants and nature. I hope that this complex layering of the actual and virtual is an appropriate analogy for Tehraj, especially during the jarring transition near the end of the track.
Post Vision Website, 2016 (In Progress)</p>

<p><a href="http://107.170.47.203/">http://107.170.47.203/</a></p>

<pre><code>This website uses a customized Django/Wagtail CMS and a from-scratch frontend using Backbone.js and Require.js with designs from Emily Dubovoy.
</code></pre>

<p>Brownstone Tutors Website, 2016</p>

<p>This website uses a from-scratch custom Django CMS. The above screenshots are from my test server to protect user privacy. SInce March the has been used to process over $1.5 million in revenue and is used every month by about sixty tutors.  Multiple open-source projects were contributed to during the development of the site, which can be seen at my Github account <a href="https://github.com/nwaxiomatic.">https://github.com/nwaxiomatic.</a>
All Natural VR, 2016
(video still)</p>

<p>(related still)</p>

<p>In this piece I wanted to explore the natural sublime through the works of Ansel Adams in the context of our cultural shift from the actual to the virtual. How does the juxtaposition of actual nature and virtual nature alter your perception of both? I devised of a world (pictured below) where residents lived in a virtual world which had chosen a framework of property ownership that did not allow objects to be deleted, and required upkeep as to stimulate their manufacturing-based virtual economy. The world soon become littered with objects and poverty since growth was not limited by material concerns which allowed a small class of residents to oppress the masses. As residents become more horrified with the utopia they had chosen, companies were invented to meet the market demand for a return to real nature. Thus ironically, All Natural VR arose.
DIE YUPPIE SCUM, 2016</p>

<p>While visiting London in 2016 I was intrigued by the graffiti visible throughout the gentrifying neighborhood of Shoreditch where I was staying. Residents on Brooklyn often complained of gentrification problems, but I had never seen graffiti as aggressive as “DIE YUPPIE SCUM” plastered to the wall. In contrast, the imagery associated with the colonization of the America’s is best summed up by the work of Bierstadt, which I had first come into contact with at the Brooklyn Museum. His paintings depict a sort of manifest destiny to the American West. Two algorithm of particular interest to me are the “space colonization” algorithm and the differential growth algorithm. The first generates a tree structure to efficiently consume virtual food stuffs (seen on the foot) and the latter grows a mesh by trying to increase surface area (seen on the hand). I wanted to use the algorithmically generated city-dwelling mutant to try and ties these ideas of city growth and displaced nature and peoples together.
Animal Skins, 2016</p>

<p>(video stills)</p>

<p>Every year, countless animals are killed and collected for sport. For this series I wanted to imagine a future where we no longer need to harvest and poach animals for their aesthetic properties. In order for this dream to become reality, there will need to be artists who are dedicated to creating an alternative aesthetic. My approach to this problem will involve hyperlifelike renditions of snake skin, animal fur, bird feathers, brain coral, and fish scales. These renditions will be photorealistic, surrealist imaginings which will hopefully remind the viewer of the living creatures from which these pieces are inspired and show that a simulated alternative is possible. The pieces will highlight various algorithmic and generative techniques.</p>

<p>I am ___., 2015</p>

<p>Largely inspired by speculative realism and the books K​ant after Duchamp and Systems We Have Loved by Thierry de Duve and Eve Meltzer, respectively, the piece I​am ___. attempts to manifest an emergent art object which grapples with the inability of any one structural ideology to fully characterize an object. The realization of this work involved making many locally logical paths with little emphasis on the global structure by following every small question to its logical conclusion. How does the hyperfine treatment of an object in locally logical systems affect the global object? Can this model of production be used to create globally emergent and autonomous objects which actively elude singular interpretation?
The piece first began as a series of self-referential images made on a computer with the help of generative algorithms and Photoshop. From these images, the goal was to physically manifest the piece as accurately as possible through whatever means necessary. This lead to the creation of five physical objects, and an augmented reality application. The augmented reality application is used to place a virtual object in the space, as well as to show a virtual representation of the piece.
The piece requires the viewers to operate the augmented reality application to finish the production of the piece, and to add titles to the piece to mark their own participation in its creation. The use of multiple self-referential objects and the ability of the application to be used across multiple devices helps create a space which both absorbs the viewers and folds over itself. I hope this materialization pulls viewers in, both physically and mentally, and asks them to participate in the autonomy of the piece.</p>

<p>Repeated Forms of Discontinuity Rotating in Place, 2014</p>

<p>In this piece I hoped to convey the failure of the futurists. Boccioni’s “Unique Forms of Continuity in Space” is stuck in place rotating over itself instead of moving forward. The aesthetics are borrowed from the Vaporwave movement in order to convey the over-saturated and accelerationist demise of the Futurists. This piece was shown at the Tate Britain during their “All Glitched Up” show in November 2014.</p>

<p>Multi-Scale Turing Patterns, 2014</p>

<p>These images were created using custom software in C++ utilizing the multi-scale turning algorithms published by Jonathan McCabe. I added modifications to the algorithm to allow coloring and new organic styles of generation.</p>

<p>Various Design Work, 2015/2016</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ny Is Killin Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/ny-is-killin-me/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/ny-is-killin-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Birds_without_space]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/birds_without_space/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/birds_without_space</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by Brancusi&rsquo;s infamous &ldquo;Bird In Space&rdquo;, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/birds_without_space/">@birds_without_space</a> represents the 9 most &ldquo;evolutionarily distinct and globally endangered&rdquo; avian species in the world due to human-related habitat loss. (You can check out <a href="http://www.edgeofexistence.org/birds/">edgeofexistence.org</a> for their complete list of species). The accompanying video piece seeks to explore the banality of such ecological horrors by flattening the traditional sculpture into a 3D render synthesizing some the largest contributors of habitat loss for these birds.</p>

<p>The images and video in the piece are all cropped at 4x5 ratio and rotated 90 degrees which maximizes the amount of space media can take up on Instagram. In choosing Instagram as the platform and framing the piece in this way I hope to provide these birds with the maximum amount of virtual space where they can repopulate symbolically through the sharing of their image. By appropriating the medium of hyper-real renderings most often used in architecture/realty and advertising, I hope to subvert these practices which allow profiting from the exploitation of land.</p>

<p>When discussing ecological horrors such as the loss of species I find the language of the Sublime and the Real to help express the ineffable magnitude of such losses. In “The Return of the Real” Hal Foster discusses techniques such as illusionism, gaze, and repetition which artists such as Gober, Sherman, and Warhol, respectively, have used in order to focus their art upon the Real.</p>

<p>The scene takes place in an old-fashioned office which could be anyone’s. This recreation of a hyper-real office space was motivated Foster’s comment that &ldquo;illusionism [for Gober] is employed not to cover up the real with simulacral surfaces but to uncover it in uncanny things&rdquo;. Living in contemporary American society makes participating in our economy of environmental havoc inevitable; we are constantly surrounded by the disastrously mundane things such as timber, meat, and electricity. The POV camera was chosen to show this trapped subject, browsing Instagram, as self-surveying, “not in phenomenological immanence (I see myself seeing myself) but in psychological estrangement (I am not what I imagined myself to be)”.</p>

<p>The extremely nontraumatic and docile act of scrolling through Instagram is repeated in a choppy loop, ad infinitum, like a reversal of Warhol’s famous “Death and Disaster” series. Here our collective trauma is not a visible horror, but a mass complacency due to the filtering of horror through the hyper-real lens of media. It feels as if the impending mass extinction &ldquo;will not occur&rdquo;. We have seen too many “gruesome picture[s] over and over again”, and now they “don’t really have any effect”. Thus, this complacent scrolling “must be repeated” but only serves to remind us of the disasters we are ignoring. This is where Foster claims “the Real ruptures the screen of repetition” and it is the now the subject that is “touched by an image”.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:62.3611111111% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BMja08yDL9c/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A video posted by Symbios (@symbios.wiki)</a> on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-11-08T15:00:49+00:00">Nov 8, 2016 at 7:00am PST</time></p></div></blockquote>


<script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safe Space]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Safe-Space/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Safe-Space</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIE YUPPIE SCUM]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/DIE-YUPPIE-SCUM/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/DIE-YUPPIE-SCUM</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Petals]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Hollow/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Hollow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Falling]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Falling/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Falling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Petals]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Petals/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Petals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lightning]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Lightning/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Lightning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bezier]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Bezier/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Bezier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decay]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Decay/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Decay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snake Skin]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Snake-Skin/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Snake-Skin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fur]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Fur/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Fur</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feathers]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Feathers/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Feathers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coral]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Coral/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Coral</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flower Patch]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Flower-Patch/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Flower-Patch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inside Looking Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Inside-Looking-Out/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Inside-Looking-Out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flamin' Hot Rainforests]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Flamin-Hot/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Flamin-Hot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2015, 6.4m acres of Indonesian rainforest were burned down from reckless slash and burning to make space for palm oil crops. These rainforests are the second most biodiverse areas on Earth and the CO2 emissions from the fires are more than the annual emissions from major economies such as the UK and Japan. <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/environment/2015/dec/15/indonesia-forest-fires-cost-twice-as-much-as-tsunami-clean-up-says-world-bank"><em>Source</em></a>.</p>

<p>To represent such a sublime atrocity is futile, and so I believe the medium should reflect this futility. I was quite inspired by Talwst Santiago’s approach to this problem in his <a href="http://talwst.com/category/sculpture-infinity/"><em>Minimized Histories</em></a> dioramas, which show tiny caricatures of hate crimes against blacks throughout history. Because most Americans’ experiences of foreign lands, such as Indonesia, and of cataclysms, such as fires, have been filtered through the lenses of tourism and movie VFX, respectively, I decided to use languages to reflect the deficiencies of representing this sublime ecological disaster.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colorful Coral]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/visual/Colorful-Coral/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/visual/Colorful-Coral</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2016 the longest coral bleaching epidemic in recorded history and scientists are worried many of the ocean&rsquo;s corals are not going to survive. I hope this colorful simulated coral growth isn&rsquo;t the only way we can appreciate these beautiful creatures in the future. <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/best-protected-great-barrier-reef-corals-are-now-dead/"><em>Source</em></a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favorite CG Music Videos]]></title>
    <link href="http://symbios.wiki/blog/CG-Music-Videos/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://symbios.wiki/blog/CG-Music-Videos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoy the symbiosis between music and visuals. Below I have collected my favorite music videos which utilize computer graphics. I will try to update this page over time as I find new works, so please check back!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Bok Bok &amp; Sweyn Jupiter - Papaya Lipgloss</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Nic Hamilton</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/123674943?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Sevdaliza - Marilyn Monroe</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Hirad Sab</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/160640015?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<p><strong>Sevdaliza - That Other Girl</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Pussykrew</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/134300640?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Oneohtrix Point Never - Sticky Drama</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Jon Rafman and Daniel Lopatin</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/144615601?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>




<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/144165513?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<p><strong>Oneohtrix Point Never - Problem Areas</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Takeshi Murata</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/71500051?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Arca - Trauma Scene 1</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Jesse Kanda</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/89944920?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Gesaffelstein - Pursuit</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Fleur &amp; Manu</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/68634031?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Bjork - All is Full of Love</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Chris Cunningham</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/43444347?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<p><strong>Bjork - Mutual Core</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Andrew Thomas Huang</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/68675931?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Bjork - Atoms for Peace - Before Your Very Eyes</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Andrew Thomas Huang</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/77253629?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Murlo - Into Mist</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Murlo</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/103281400?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>QT - Hey QT</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Bradley &amp; Pablo</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/122527024?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Panda Bear - Boys Latin</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Isaiah Saxon and Sean Hellfritsch</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/113544877?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Harrison - Vanilla (feat. Ryan Hemsworth)</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Alex McLeod</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/zi5ghKAjlg8" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Thug Entrancer - Death After Life I</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Milton Melvin Croissant III</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/84716880?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Tsaik - Tehraj</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Symbios</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/147827031?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Giant Claw - DARK WEB 003</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: James Webster</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/108841750?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Son Lux - Breathe Out</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Adrian Moyse &amp; Junta</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/148853961?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>SBTRKT - New Dorp New York</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Fons Schiedon</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/152730891?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Yeasayer - I Am Chemistry</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: New Media Limited</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/151002965?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>Clark - Winter Linn</strong></p>

<p>Directed by: Chris Hewitt</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/111743736?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>


<hr />

<p><strong>OL - Lum Edit</strong></p>

<p>Directed By: Mark Fingerhut</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/110497218?loop=1" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen> </iframe></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
